Earlier in the course we talk about projects and operations.
I mean this is a really important topic and it's sometimes a theme it seems throughout the Pinback guy.
But we're going to nail this down once and for all here and we're not going to look at it anymore.
But I just want to be clear we have a good understanding of projects and operations especially when
we talk about related areas of project management because projects and operations are obviously related.
Both have employees.
You have employees that work in operations and then those employees may be part of a project team that
are working on projects.
So our project team members need to understand there's a difference between ongoing work and a project
which is temporary work.
So both have employees but they need to understand the concept of operations or projects.
Both have limited resources both have only so much people only so many hours in the day and so much
money or typically both.
They only have so much money in a project.
You only have so much money in operations both operations and projects are designed you execute it.
One's going on forever and the other short term is it's short not short term it's temporary it's temporary
it's executed and it's managed.
So projects and operations have those characteristics in common projects and operations.
We also have the idea that they are temporary.
So projects are temporary you know what about operations operations are not necessarily temporary.
They can be ongoing that we want the organization to last forever and ever.
So projects we think about developing new products or implementing services and strategy.
There's that Mac D we saw earlier moving adding changing deleting implementing a new service or solution.
And there's the operational transfer so that we take the thing that we've created and now it moves over
into production or operations operations are ongoing repetitive actions like procurement accounting
finance marketing sales.
It's just the wheels are the engine of the organization or projects are special.
They're over here.
Unique from the day to day operations of maintenance is a good example of operations.
It's the core business functions.
All right that's it.
We're not going to talk about operations or or the difference between the two anymore I think you've
got this down ice I promise no more of that.
Keep moving forward.
I'll see you in the next lecture.